#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated and adaptable programmer with strong communication and problem solving skills acquired from 4 years of military service as a health care specialist. Quick learner and comfortable with new technologies. Ability to lead and take initiative to accomplish tasks

- .Net, Spring Boot and Django.
- C# and Java programming languages.
  SQL and MySQL, Entity Framework
  HTML, CSS and bootstrap.
  Knowledge in Mac and Win
- Angularis

  - Knowledge in Mac and Windows OS.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**United States Army Health Care Specialist** 

2013-Current

### 82<sup>ND</sup> Airborne Division, Fort Bragg, NC

Provide Emergency Medical Treatment, Limited Primary Care, health protection and evacuation in a variety of operational and clinical settings.

- Supervised, instructed and trained twenty soldiers, as a team leader making them proficient and up to date with required medical knowledge.
- Maintained accountability of nine medical vehicles and inspected vehicle to ensure they were mechanically operational.
- Maintained health records and clinical files of more than 400 soldiers.

### 173 Airborne Brigade, Vicenza Italy

Served as a line medic, an ambulance driver and as a clinical assistant at the base clinic.

- Instructed Combat life Saver Courses, allowing more than 200 soldiers to advances first aid procedures.
- Provided medical support in four major training operations, more than 40 military training events, working with service members from six foreign countries.

## University of Wisconsin-Stout, Menomonie, WI **Physics Department Physics Tutor**

2012-2013

Mentored physics students with homework and understanding general Mechanical and Thermodynamics principles. Addressed any student queries in a timely manner.

### **Ashish Singh**

### (910)813-8195

### Ashish.Singh4086@outlook.com

- Maintained records of each tutoring sessions allowing the department supervisor to generate schedules and tutoring plans.
- Researching, collecting and providing course related examples to the students, to better prepare them for the examination.

# University of Wisconsin-Stout, Menomonie, WI

2012-2013

# **Disability Services**

## **Technical Web Developer**

Provided upgrades and maintenance support to the Disability Services website. Provide better user interfaces and add new section as required by the department supervisor.

- Added a new home page with welcome message, faculty information and a contact section with vital contact information.
- Added links to services provided by the department like Eligibility, Meet the Staff and Student Resources.

# Heartland Business Systems, Lisle, IL

2012-2012

### **Engineering Associate**

Provide fellow Engineers with network installation assistance, review, validation, and optimization of systems and protocols. Obtain knowledge on a variety of technologies and platforms as directed by your manager and customer demand.

- Assisted team leader to disassemble about 100 laptops that required parts upgrade.
- Imaged more than 200 laptops and Desktop computers for use by the company.

# University of Wisconsin-Stout, Menomonie, WI Ask5000

2011-2012

### **Help Desk Assistant**

Assist Applicants, students, faculty and staff with their campus-technology needs and answer many general technology questions.

- Resolved more than 200 technical tickets created by the students and faculty.
- Effectively imaged more than 400 computers both on Mac and Windows operating systems.

### **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

• Microsoft Software & Systems Academy (MSSA): Cloud Application Development, Designing and developing programs in .NET, C#, SQL and AZURE.